A Guide to the Studies of the Virginia Division of Legislative Services, 1978-2000.
Library of Virginia
- Studies (Accession 40914), 1973-1998., Extent: 27 cubic feet (27 boxes)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Continuation of Services to Young Adults Exiting Publicly Funded Prograns (HJR 103) - Articles, 1994. (Box 17)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Continuation of Services to Young Adults Exiting Publicly Funded Prograns (HJR 103) - Correspondence, 1994. (Box 17)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Continuation of Services to Young Adults Exiting Publicly Funded Prograns (HJR 103) - Legislation, 1994. (Box 17)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Continuation of Services to Young Adults Exiting Publicly Funded Prograns (HJR 103) - Presentations/Handouts, 1994. (Box 17)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Continuation of Services to Young Adults Exiting Publicly Funded Prograns (HJR 103) - Public hearing comments, 1994. (Box 17)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Continuation of Services to Young Adults Exiting Publicly Funded Prograns (HJR 103) - Reports, 1994. (Box 17)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Dropouts and Ways to Promote Self-Esteem Among Youths and Adults - Agendas, 1992-1995. (Box 18)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Prevention of School Crime and Violence - Agendas/meetings/minutes, 1992-1994. (Box 18)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Prevention of School Crime and Violence - Correspondence, 1992. (Box 18)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Prevention of School Crime and Violence - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 18)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Prevention of School Crime and Violence - Reports, 1992-1994. (Box 18)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Prevention of School Crime and Violence - Research materials, 1992-1994. (Box 18)
  - Dept. of Education - RFP for Proposal Team on At-Risk Students - Correspondence, 1992. (Box 18)
  - Dept. of Education - RFP for Proposal Team on At-Risk Students - Miscellaneous, 1992. (Box 18)
  - Commission to Stimulate Personal Initiative to Overcome Poverty (HJR 74) - Correspondence, 1992. (Box 18)
  - Commission to Stimulate Personal Initiative to Overcome Poverty (HJR 74) - Meetings, 1992Aug, Dec. (Box 18)
  - Commission to Stimulate Personal Initiative to Overcome Poverty (HJR 74) - Meeting, 1993 May. (Box 18)
  - Commission to Stimulate Personal Initiative to Overcome Poverty (HJR 74) - Reports, 1992. (Box 18)
  - Commission to Stimulate Personal Initiative to Overcome Poverty (HJR 74) - Research materials, 1992. (Box 18)
  - State Post-Secondary Review Entity, 1993-1994. (Box 18)
  - Report Concerning the Interagency Coordination Efforts of the Joint Board Liaison Committee on HIV-AIDS - Articles, 1989. (Box 19)
  - Report Concerning the Interagency Coordination Efforts of the Joint Board Liaison Committee on HIV-AIDS - Correspondence, 1989. (Box 19)
  - Report Concerning the Interagency Coordination Efforts of the Joint Board Liaison Committee on HIV-AIDS - Handouts, 1989. (Box 19)
  - Report Concerning the Interagency Coordination Efforts of the Joint Board Liaison Committee on HIV-AIDS - Reports, 1989. (Box 19)
  - Report Concerning the Interagency Coordination Efforts of the Joint Board Liaison Committee on HIV-AIDS - Research materials, 1989. (Box 19)
  - Health Services Access Program and Standard Health Services Program / Essential Health Services Panel (SB 506) - Agendas/meetings/minutes, 1992-1993. (Box 19)
  - Health Services Access Program and Standard Health Services Program / Essential Health Services Panel (SB 506) - Articles, 1992-1993. (Box 19)
  - Health Services Access Program and Standard Health Services Program / Essential Health Services Panel (SB 506) - Correspondence, 1992-1993. (Box 19)
  - Health Services Access Program and Standard Health Services Program / Essential Health Services Panel (SB 506) - Miscellaneous, 1992-1993. (Box 19)
  - Health Services Access Program and Standard Health Services Program / Essential Health Services Panel (SB 506) - Reports, 1992-1993. (Box 19)
  - Health Services Access Program and Standard Health Services Program / Essential Health Services Panel (SB 506) - Research materials, 1992-1993. (Box 19)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Financial Impact of Third Party Reimbursement of the Commonwealth's Pharmacies - Agendas/Minutes/Meeting notes, 1993-1995. (Box 20)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Financial Impact of Third Party Reimbursement of the Commonwealth's Pharmacies - Committee schedule, 1993-1995. (Box 20)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Financial Impact of Third Party Reimbursement of the Commonwealth's Pharmacies - Correspondence, 1993-1995. (Box 20)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Financial Impact of Third Party Reimbursement of the Commonwealth's Pharmacies - Handouts, 1993-1995. (Box 20)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Financial Impact of Third Party Reimbursement of the Commonwealth's Pharmacies - Reports, 1993-1995. (Box 20)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Financial Impact of Third Party Reimbursement of the Commonwealth's Pharmacies - Research materials, 1993-1995. (Box 20)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying School Dropouts and Self-Esteem - Agendas/Minutes/Meeting notes, 1994. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying School Dropouts and Self-Esteem - Correspondence, 1994. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying School Dropouts and Self-Esteem - Miscellaneous, 1993. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying School Dropouts and Self-Esteem - Reports, 1994. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying School Dropouts and Self-Esteem - Research materials, 1991-1994. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Certain Emergency Medical Services Training and Governance Issues - Agendas/Minutes/Meeting notes, 1995-1996. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Certain Emergency Medical Services Training and Governance Issues - Correspondence, 1995-1996. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Certain Emergency Medical Services Training and Governance Issues - Public hearing, 1995 Sept. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Certain Emergency Medical Services Training and Governance Issues - Research materials, 1995. (Box 21)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Agendas/Minutes/Meeting notes, 1994. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Articles, 1993-1995. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Correspondence, 1994. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Drafts, 1995. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Legislative draft proposals, 1993-1995. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Notes, 1995. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Presentations, 1993-1995. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Reports, 1993-1995. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Reports (HD 70), 1996. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Research materials, 1995. (Box 22)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Research materials (other states), 1993-1995. (Box 22)
  - Select Committee to Study Alternative Methods of School Construction and Renovation Funding - Agendas, 1994-1995. (Box 23)
  - Select Committee to Study Alternative Methods of School Construction and Renovation Funding - Legislative draft proposals, 1994-1995. (Box 23)
  - Select Committee to Study Alternative Methods of School Construction and Renovation Funding - Research materials, 1994-1995. (Box 23)
  - Committee on Education Technology Funding - Agendas, 1994-1995. (Box 23)
  - Committee on Education Technology Funding - Presentations, 1994-1995. (Box 23)
  - Committee on Education Technology Funding - Reports, 1994-1995. (Box 23)
  - Committee on Education Technology Funding - Research materials, 1994-1995. (Box 23)
  - Commission on Equity and Efficiency in Education - Agendas/Minutes/Meeting notes, 1992-1995. (Box 23)
  - Commission on Equity and Efficiency in Education - Correspondence, 1992-1995. (Box 23)
  - Commission on Equity and Efficiency in Education - Handouts, 1992-1995. (Box 23)
  - Commission on Equity and Efficiency in Education - Reports, 1992-1995. (Box 23)
  - Commission on Equity and Efficiency in Education - Research materials, 1992-1995. (Box 23)
  - Commission on Equity and Efficiency in Education - Study plans, 1992-1995. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Block Grants (Community Service) - Agendas/Minutes/Meeting notes, 1993-1995. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Block Grants (Community Service) - Correspondence, 1993-1995. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Block Grants (Community Service) - Presentations, 1993-1995. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Block Grants (Community Service) - Reports, 1993-1995. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Block Grants (Community Service) - Research materials, 1993-1995. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Feasibility of Allowing Certified Soil Scientists to Approve Septic Sites and Systems - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Feasibility of Allowing Certified Soil Scientists to Approve Septic Sites and Systems - Research materials, 1993. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Feasibility of Allowing Certified Soil Scientists to Approve Septic Sites and Systems - Research materials (Other states), 1993. (Box 23)
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Feasibility of Allowing Certified Soil Scientists to Approve Septic Sites and Systems - Reports 1993. (Box 23)
  - Commission on the Future of Higher Education in Virginia - Agendas/Meeting records, 1994-1996. (Box 24)
  - Commission on the Future of Higher Education in Virginia - Handouts, 1994-1996. (Box 24)
  - Commission on the Future of Higher Education in Virginia - Legislation, 1994-1996. (Box 24)
  - Commission on the Future of Higher Education in Virginia - Reports, 1994-1996. (Box 24)
  - Commission on the Future of Higher Education in Virginia - Reports (SD 26, 1996), 1996. (Box 24)
  - Commission on the Future of Higher Education in Virginia - Research materials, 1994-1996. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Agendas/Meeting notes/Minutes, 1993. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Articles, 1993. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Miscellaneous, 1993. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Presentations/Handouts, 1993. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Public hearings, 1993. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Educational Museums and the Appropriate Level of Public Support to be Provided Such Institutions Pursuant to HJR 30 - Research materials, 1993. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Need for Academic Preparation, Financial Aid and Incentive Programs to Encourage Minorities to Pursue Post-Secondary Education and Training - Agendas/Meeting note/Minutes, 1993-1994. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Need for Academic Preparation, Financial Aid and Incentive Programs to Encourage Minorities to Pursue Post-Secondary Education and Training - Correspondence, 1993-1994. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Need for Academic Preparation, Financial Aid and Incentive Programs to Encourage Minorities to Pursue Post-Secondary Education and Training - Legislation, 1993-1994. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Need for Academic Preparation, Financial Aid and Incentive Programs to Encourage Minorities to Pursue Post-Secondary Education and Training - Presentations/Handouts, 1993-1994. (Box 24)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Agendas/Meeting records/Minutes, 1992. (Box 25)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Conference materials, 1992. (Box 25)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 25)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Correspondence, 1992. (Box 25)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Miscellaneous, 1992. (Box 25)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Reports, 1991-1993. (Box 25)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Research materials, 1991-1993. (Box 25)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Agendas/Meeting records/Minutes, 1992. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Agendas/Meeting records/Minutes, 1991. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Agendas/Meeting records/Minutes, 1990. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Correspondence, 1992. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Correspondence, 1991. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Correspondence, 1990. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Miscellaneous, 1990. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Reports, 1991. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Reports, 1990. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Research materials, 1992. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Research materials, 1991. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Research materials, 1990. (Box 26)
  - Joint Subcommittee on Maternal and Perinatal Drug Exposure and Abuse and Its Impact on Subsidized Adoptions and Foster Care - Research materials, 1990-1993. (Box 27)
- Studies (Accession 42271), 1983-1998., Extent: 80 cubic feet (80 boxes)
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Comprehensive Conflict of Interest Act (SJR 68), 1986. (Box 1)
    - Study plans/objectives, research materials, legislation, correspondence, handouts, audiotapes.
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Role of the General Assembly in the Development of a Competitive Electric Utility Industry in the Commonwealth (SJR 118), 1996-1997. (Box 2-3)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, other states, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts, audiotapes (Senate Document 28, 1997).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Ways to Reduce Emmissions from Coal-Carrying Railroad Cars (SJR 267), 1995. (Box 4)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research materials, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts, videotapes (Senate Document 58, 1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Funding Requirements of the Unemployment Compensation Trust Fund, 1995. (Box 4)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, other states, correspondence, presentations/handouts, audiotapes (Senate Document 22, 1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying Ways to Assist and Encourage Small Business in Virginia (SJR 128), 1994. (Box 4)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans/objectives, reports, research material, other states, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts (Senate Document 38, 1995).
  - Future of Higher Education / Matching Virginia Higher Education's Strengths and the Commonwealth's Needs (SJR 139), 1994-1996. (Box 5)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, legislation, correspondence, presentations/handouts (Senate Document 26, 1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Efficacy and Appropriateness of Creating a School Incentive Reward Program in the Commonwealth (HJR 165), 1996-1997. (Box 5)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, correspondence, presentations/handouts (House Document 71, 1997).
  - Commission on Accountability for Educational Excellence (HJR 168), 1996-1997. (Box 5)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, correspondence, presentations/handouts, (House Document 88, 1997).
  - Commission on the Future of Public Education / Blueprint for Educational Excellence (HJR 196), 1997-1998. (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (House Document 48, 1998).
  - Commission on the Future of Public Education (HJR 196), 1996-1998. (Box 6)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts (House Document 48, 1998).
  - Non-Credit Education for Workforce Training (HJR 622), 1997-1998. (Box 7)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, plans, research material, correspondence, presentations/handouts (House Document 85, 1998).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Administration of Local Anesthesia by Licensed Dental Hygienists (SJR 1997), 1997. (Box 8)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, correspondence, presentations/handouts.
  - Joint Subcommittee to Examine the Shortfall of Dental Hygienists in the Commonwealth (HJR 81), 1996-1997. (Box 6)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, research material, legislation, correspondence, public hearing comments (House Document 36, 1997).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Medicaid Reimbursement Billing Program for the Public Schools (SJR 182), 1998. (Box 8)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, correspondence, presentations/handouts.
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Commonwealth's Current Laws and Policies Related to Acute and Cancer Pain Management (SJR 71 - 1994, SJR 583 - 1995, HJR 256 - 1997, HJR 65 - 1997, HJR 172 - 1998), 1994-1998. (Box 9-11)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, other states, legislation, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts, symposium materials (b09) (House Document 94, 1998).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Child Protective Services System in the Commonwealth (HJR 502), 1995-1996. (Box 12-13)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans/objectives, reports, research material, other states, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts, public hearing comments, also includes information gathered by 1993 subcommittee of the House Health, Welfare and Institutions re: child abuse and neglect and child protective services (House Document 74, 1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee Study for Supervised Housing Outside Institutional Committment (SJR 220), 1989-1990. (Box 14)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans/objectives, research material, other states, correspondence, articles (Senate Document 436, 1990).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Need for Restructuring the Commonwealth's Local Social Services Delivery System (SJR 213 and HJR 314, 1991; SJR 135, 1992), 1991-1993. (Box 15)
    - Minutes/meeting notes, study plans/objectives, reports, research material, correspondence, articles, audiotapes (Senate Document 45, 1993).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Commonwealth's Adoption Laws (HJR 100), 1994-1995. (Box 16)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans/objectives, reports, research material, other state laws, legislation, correspondence (House Document 65, 1995).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Demise of Independent Pharmacies (HJR 158), 1996-1998. (Box 17)
    - Agendas, study plans/objectives, reports, research material, other state laws, correspondence, articles (House Document 91, 1998).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Needs of Foreign-Born Individuals Residing in the Commonwealth (HJR 97, 1992; HJR 599, 1995), 1992-1996. (Box 18-19)
    - Minutes/meeting notes, study plans/objectives, reports, research material, other state laws, correspondence, articles, audiotapes, Immigrant and Refugee Policy Council materials (House Document 75, 1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee Studying the Effects of Deinstitutionalization (HJR 39, 1994; HJR 549, 1995), 1994-1997. (Box 20)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, legislation, correspondence, presentations (House Document 14, 1997).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Feasibility of Allowing Certified Soil Scientists to Approve Septic Sites and Systems (SJR 366, 1993), 1993. (Box 20)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, study plans/objectives, reports, research material, correspondence, presentations (No published Senate Document).
  - Public Health Implications of Licensing Radiologic Technology Practitioners (HJR 665, 1993; HJR 190, 1994; HJR 617, 1995), 1993-1996. (Box 20)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, other state laws, correspondence, audiotapes (House Document 3, 1996).
  - Joint Subcommittee to Study the Comprehensive Services Act (SJR 93, 1996), 1996. (Box 21)
    - Agendas, minutes/meeting notes, reports, research material, correspondence, articles, presentations/handouts, public hearing comments (No published Senate Document).